3 chapter 4 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public
domain Black Beauty by Anna suul chapter 4 Berwick
Park At this time I used to stand in the stable and my coat was brushed every day
until it sha like a rook's wing. It was early in May, when there came
a man from Squire Gordon who took me away to the hall. My master said goodbye be a
good horse, and always do your best.” I could not say goodbye so I put my
nose into his hand; he patted me kindly, and I left my first
home. As I lived some years with Squire Gordon, I may as well tell something about the
place. Squire Gordon's park skirted the village of Berwick It was entered by a
large iron gate, at which stood the first lodge, and then you trotted along on a
smooth road between clumps of large old trees; then another lodge and another
gate, which brought you to the house and the gardens. Beyond this lay the home paddock,
the old orchard, and the stables. There was accommodation for many
horses and carriages; but I need only describe the stable into which I was
taken; this was very roomy, with four good stalls; a large swinging window opened
into the yard, which made it pleasant and airy. The first stall was a large square
one, shut in behind with a wooden gate; the others were common stalls, good
stalls, but not nearly so large; it had a low rack for hay and a low manger for
corn; it was called a loose box, because the horse that was put into it was not
tied up, but left loose, to do as he liked.
It is a great thing to have a loose box. Into this fine box the groom put me;
it was clean, sweet, and airy. I never was in a better box than that, and the sides
were not so high but that I could see all that went on through the iron rails
that were at the top. He gave me some very nice oats, he patted me, spoke kindly,
and then went away. When I had eaten my corn I looked around
In the stall next to mine stood a little fat gray pony, with a thick mane and tail,
a very pretty head, and a per little nose.
I put my head up to the iron rails at
the top of my box, and said, “How do you do?
What is your name?” He turned around as far as his
halter would allow, held up his head, and said, “My name is Merry legs I am very
handsome; I carry the young ladies on my back, and sometimes I take our mistress
out in the low chair there They think a great deal of me, and so does James. Are
you going to live next door to me in the
box?” I said, “Yes.” “Well, then,” he said, “I hope you were good tempered I do not like
anyone next door who bites.” Just then a horse's head looked
over from the stall beyond; the ears were laid back, and the eye looked rather
ill-tempered. This was a tall chestnut mare, with a long handsome neck. She
looked AC crossed me and said: “So it is
you who have turned me out of my box; it
is a very strange thing for a cult like
you to come and turn a lady out of her own
home.” “I beg your pardon,” I said, “I have turned no one out; the man who brought me
put me here, and I had nothing to do with
it; and as to my being a cult I am turned
4 years old and I'm a grown-up horse. I never had words yet with horse or mare,
and it is my wish to live at peace.” “Well,” she said, “we shall see. Of course, I
do not want to have words with a young thing like you.” I said no
more. In the afternoon, when she went out Mery legs told me all about
it. “The thing is this,” said Mary legs Ginger has a bad habit of biting and
snapping; that is why they call her Ginger, and when she was in the loose box
she used to snap very much. One day she bit James in the arm and made it bleed,
and so Miss Flora and Miss Jesse who were very fond of me, were afraid to come
into the stable. They used to bring me nice things to eat, an apple or a carrot,
or a piece of bread, but after Ginger stood in that box they dared not come,
and I missed them very much. I hope they will now come again, if you do not bite
or snap.” I told him I never bit anything but grass, hay, and corn, and could not think
what pleasure Ginger found it.
“Well, I don't think she does find pleasure,” says Mery legs it is just a bad
habit; she says no one was ever kind to her, and why should she not bite? Of
course, it is a very bad habit; but I'm sure, if all she says be true, she must
have been very ill used before she came here JN does all he can to please her,
and James does all he can, and our master never uses a whip if a horse acts right;
so I think she might be good tempered here.
You see,” he said, with a wise look, “I am 12
years old; I know a great deal, and I can
tell you there is not a better place for a horse all around the country than this.
John is the best groom that ever was; he has been here 14 years; and you never saw
such a kind boy as James is; so that it is all Ginger's own fault that she did
not stay in that box end of chapter 4